unicast.com 2001-04-05

# COMPANY - Privacy Statement

As such, Unicast supports an individual's right to privacy on the Web by providing the following information about Unicast's advertising unit, The SUPERSTITIAL®. 

**Privacy and SUPERSTITIALs:**

**What is a SUPERSTITIAL?**

The SUPERSTITIAL format from Unicast offers Web publishers, networks, agencies and advertisers a viable vehicle for online advertising. Introduced by Unicast to the US marketplace in May 1999, the SUPERSTITIAL has established a new Internet advertising category - one with the potential to become a standard that supports the long-term evolution of the Web as a global mass medium. The SUPERSTITIAL format is proprietary to Unicast. 

SUPERSTITIALs are highly interactive, non-banner Internet commercials that can feature full animation, sound and graphics without slowing down the delivery of Web site content or the user's Web browsing experience \- regardless of a user's connection speed. 

SUPERSTITIAL ads can be up to 100K in file size and are created using the preferred authoring tools of the Internet industry - including Macromedia Flashœ. 

The Unicast patent-pending cache-and-play delivery system behind the SUPERSTITIAL format minimizes the latency problems often experienced with streaming online advertising solutions. Ads are fully pre-loaded before playing and play only during a logical, user-initiated break in surfing, triggered by a mouse click. 

This process standardizes the SUPERSTITIAL ad experience, ensuring that every user gets a consistent and complete ad message. This unique delivery system is what differentiates pre-loaded SUPERSTITIAL ads from streaming interstitial and banner ads. 

According to Millward Brown Interactive, the leading interactive advertising research firm, SUPERSTITIAL ads more effectively convey integrated, compelling advertising messages and deliver higher ROI than any other online advertising format available. 

SUPERSTITIALs can be used to achieve multiple advertising goals, including branding, direct marketing, commerce and entertainment. Additionally, because SUPERSTITIAL ad units are outside of the banner space, they create an entirely new advertising tier for Web publishers and advertisers. 

**How does The SUPERSTITIAL format's proprietary delivery system work?**

SUPERSTITIAL ads do not interfere with Web site content loading. Instead, SUPERSTITIAL ads are loaded and assembled in the user's browser cache while the user is viewing or reading Web page content. The SUPERSTITIAL plays only after the ad file is fully assembled. 

To facilitate the assembly of SUPERSTITIAL ads in the browser cache, Unicast utilizes a JAVA¬ applet (an applet is a compilation of code that coordinates the transmission of content or data): 

1\. The ad-loading process waits to begin until the user becomes "idle" (i.e., not using their modem/connection to gather content from the host Web site). 

2\. Unicast's JAVA applet is loaded into the browser cache. 

3\. In coordination with the Web site or the appropriate ad management system, The SUPERSTITIAL ad is loaded and pre-assembled in the browser cache. 

4\. During the loading process, if a user initiates the modem (by requesting new content from the Web site), the loading process pauses. The loading process then picks up where it left off after the user becomes idle again. 

5\. Once the SUPERSTITIAL ad is fully loaded and assembled in the browser cache, when the user clicks to a new page, the SUPERSTITIAL ad will play in its own window while the new content finishes loading. 

6\. Because the ad is playing from the browser cache (i.e., "locally"), it will begin playing almost instantaneously upon launching. 

7\. SUPERSTITIAL ads can be closed at any time if the user clicks on the corner "X" box of the browser window in which the ad is playing. 

8\. If the user lets the SUPERSTITAL play to completion without interacting with the ad by clicking on it, the ad will self-close. 

**Does the SUPERSTITIAL loading process interfere with my surfing experience or slow my connection speed?**

This loading process is invisible to the user and does not affect the user's Web surfing experience. 

**Once loaded, does the SUPERSTITIAL ad file or Unicast's JAVA applet negatively affect my computer or my connection at all?**

While in a user's cache, Unicast's JAVA applet does not impact the user's computer, processor speed or connectivity. Likewise, while a SUPERSTITIAL ad file is in a user's browser cache (either partially or fully loaded), the user's Web experience is not affected. 

**Is Unicast's JAVA applet a permanent download into my computer?**

Unicast's JAVA applet and all SUPERSTITIAL ad files are pre-loaded into the browser cache: the temporary storage area for the Web content a viewer sees while surfing the Internet. (The temporary storage of content in the cache allows users to easily access recently visited Web site content. For example, when users press the "Back" button within the browser window, they are triggering content from the browser cache.) 

Once in the browser cache, Unicast's JAVA applet remains there until it is automatically deleted through the course of time or until a user manually flushes the cache. ("Flushing" is a term for the elimination of content from the browser cache.) 

Automatic deletion of cached content occurs when the browser cache becomes completely filled with cached content such as Web site content files and images. The older content is deleted from the cache to allow new content to be stored. 

For many browsers, users can set their browser preferences to automatically flush the browser cache according to a time schedule of their choosing. Otherwise, a user can manually flush the browser cache at any time. Flushing the cache eliminates Unicast's JAVA applet and any fully or partially loaded SUPERSTITIAL ad files from the user's cache until the next time a SUPERSTITIAL ad is served to the user. 

**How can I tell when Unicast's JAVA applet or SUPERSTITIAL ad files have been loaded into my cache?**

If a user sees a SUPERSTITIAL ad, Unicast's JAVA applet and the SUPERSTITIAL ad file have been loaded into the browser cache. To eliminate Unicast's JAVA applet and any fully or partially loaded SUPERSTITIAL ad files from the cache, a user can manually flush the browser cache. 

**What happens to a SUPERSTITIAL ad file after it plays?**

Upon completion of the ad's play, the SUPERSTITIAL ad file remains in the browser cache according to the user's browser specifications. Again, to remove Unicast's JAVA applet and any SUPERSTITIAL ad files, the user can manually flush the browser cache at any time. 

**What happens to a partially loaded SUPERSTITIAL ad file if a user leaves a Web site before the ad has played?**

If a user leaves a site before a SUPERSTITIAL ad has been able to fully assemble, the partially loaded ad remains in the browser cache. Should the user return to a Web site that is part of the media buy for that particular SUPERSTITIAL ad campaign, the SUPERSTITIAL ad will continue loading into the browser cache from the point at which it had left off when the user becomes idle on the new site. 

If the user never returns to a site that is part of the media buy for that particular SUPERSTITIAL ad, the partially loaded ad file will remain in the browser cache until it is automatically deleted according to the user's browser specifications or until the user manually flushes the browser cache. 

**What kind of information is collected about users who see a SUPERSTITIAL ad?**

Unicast logs click stream and impression data (i.e., how many SUPERSTITIAL ads played and how many users click on an ad) for every SUPERSTITIAL ad campaign and may collect anonymous domain, browser and system configuration information from computers that have been served a SUPERSTITIAL advertisement. This information is not personally identifiable and does not include name, address, phone or email address. Anonymous domain information is collected, stored securely on Unicast's server and analyzed by Unicast. 

On behalf of the advertisers and Web sites for which it serves SUPERSTITIAL ad campaigns, Unicast also may aggregate additional information about users' interactions within SUPERSTITIAL ads. This tracking includes multiple clicks to different products or services featured in an ad, and depth and length of interaction within the ad. 

The scope of information gathered by Unicast regarding user interaction within SUPERSTITIAL ads varies from campaign to campaign and is directed by the goals of the specific advertiser. All tracking information Unicast monitors is completely anonymous and is reported in aggregate. 

If the user enters information, including personally identifiable information, in a form or comment area of an ad, this information is collected by Unicast for the advertiser, as well. Other than what the user voluntarily provides, all information is anonymous and personally unidentifiable. 

**What does Unicast do with the anonymous information it collects around SUPERSTITIAL ad campaigns?**

The anonymous tracking information Unicast monitors surrounding each SUPERSTITIAL campaign is reported in aggregate to the advertiser and participating Web sites by Unicast or the participating third party ad-serving network. 

Unicast retains aggregate domain, browser and system configuration information on the computers that have been served a SUPERSTITIAL advertisement. Unicast also retains click stream and impression data for each SUPERSTITIAL campaign. Unicast does this in order to continually analyze the market penetration and effectiveness of the SUPERSTITIAL format and to substantiate licensing fees charged to Unicast's customers. 

Occasionally, Unicast may share the anonymous tracking information it collects with third parties who perform technical audits of the accuracy of such data for the benefit of Unicast as well as its advertisers, participating Web sites and participating third party ad-serving networks. 

All such auditors enter into contracts with Unicast which contain confidentiality clauses and the audit results are reported to Unicast and shared only with Web sites and networks under contracts with Unicast containing confidentiality clauses. 

**Does Unicast ever collect any personally identifiable information about users who see a SUPERSTITIAL ad?**

In some cases, users may voluntarily provide personal information in response to a specific ad where the advertiser requests such information so that the advertiser may contact interested parties, provide requested product literature and receive user feedback for processing. 

For example, a user may enter their name, email address and/or mailing address when requesting more information from the advertiser. 

In these cases, the voluntarily provided user information is reported to the advertiser by Unicast. Thereafter the privacy policy of the advertiser applies to this information. Users are advised not to provide personal information if they do not want it used by the advertiser. 

Common Market users authorize the export of this personal information to the United States when they provide such information. 

Unicast does not keep, record or share this personally identifiable information with any other outside parties, nor does Unicast keep or utilize this information for internal purposes in any way. 

Unicast may, at the request of the advertiser, temporarily store the personal information on its servers for a brief period (now up to 30 days) as an added service to the advertiser, but in all cases Unicast is acting as a conduit to the advertiser. At the end of the storage period, Unicast delivers the personal information to the advertiser or its agent and deletes it completely from the Unicast server. 

From time to time, Unicast may have special promotions or user surveys or other events which are not part of its regular business activities and which involve the collection of personally identifiable information. Separate privacy notices will be included within event materials if these differ from this notice. 

Any personally identifiable information collected through a SUPERSTITIAL ad is not matched to any behavioral or anonymous information collected by Unicast. 

**Does Unicast target or manage the viewing of SUPERSTITIAL advertising to users?**

Unicast is dedicated to providing sites and their users a positive Web surfing experience. In addition to being polite, SUPERSTITIAL technology has the capacity to manage the frequency with which users are exposed to a SUPERSTITIAL ad. This helps insure that users are not bombarded with repeat and messages. 

The means used by Unicast to manage the frequency of SUPERSTITIAL ads a user is exposed to during a day or over an extended time period is in the form of a [cookie](http://webopedia.internet.com/TERM/c/cookie.html)\- a small file placed in a web browser that stores information. 

**Does unicast compile user profiles in order to monitor the frequency of SUPERSTITIAL ads?**

No. Unicast controls the delivery system that brings SUPERSTITIAL advertisements to users and the number of times a user may see a specific SUPERSTITIAL advertisement by employing an _anonymous_ cookie. The Unicast frequency-management cookie collects no personally identifiable information and contains no user ID. 

**What if I want to opt-out of the Unicast frequency-management cookie?**

Unicast has provided a page where users may opt-out of the frequency-management cookie used to manage SUPERSTITIAL ad frequency. However, _once a user has opted out of the frequency-management cookie, Unicast can no longer recognize that user's browser from one visit to the next, hence the user may receive the same ad multiple times.Click here to opt-out _of the Unicast frequency-management cookie. 

**If I opt-out of the SUPERSTITIAL frequency-management cookie, can I decide later that I want to opt-in again in order to manage the frequency with which I see SUPERSTITIAL ads?**

Unicast has provided a page where a user may opt-in again after opting out. The opt-in page will reset the user's browser to again allow the Unicast frequency-management cookie to manage the frequency of SUPERSTITISL ads. Click here to opt-in again  to the Unicast frequency-management cookie. 

**Do Unicast's advertisers or Web site partners have the ability to target their SUPERSTITIAL advertising or to compile profiles on users that see their SUPERSTITIAL advertisements?**

Advertising content delivered via the Unicast SUPERSTITIAL system may contain third-party cookies. Advertisers, and third party companies acting on behalf of advertisers (such as an ad serving company or an ad agency), use third-party cookies to judge the effectiveness of and target their SUPERSTITIAL ad campaigns. 

While Unicast's SUPERSTITIAL format delivers the ad content which may allow a third-party cookie to be set, such cookies are not within Unicast's control and the information they collect is reported back to the third party directly, not through Unicast. Third-party cookies are placed and tracked by the advertiser or by a third-party company. Unicast does not have the access to the information tracked by third-party cookies. 

Most third-party cookies anonymously track the Web browsing habits of users and their interactions with the ads they view. However, users should be aware that some cookies can collect other types of information, including personally identifiable information. 

While Unicast itself does not have access to the information tracked by third-party cookies set through SUPERSTITIAL advertisements, there are cases when the third party may agree to share such information with Unicast. Such information sharing is done on an aggregate and anonymous basis, and does not include any personally indentifiable information collected by the third party. 

The issue of third party cookies is a matter between the users and the advertisers and/or the third party company representing the advertiser, not involving Unicast. This information is provided by Unicast as a service to users who may be unaware of third party cookies. 

To learn more about third party cookies and the companies that may employ third party cookies within SUPERSTITIAL advertisements, please visit the following companies' privacy policies: 

**Are Unicast's servers and the information stored on them secure? Is the information accessible by users?**

Unicast has taken industry-standard steps to secure information on its servers. Only Unicast personnel are authorized to access the company's servers. Because all stored information is anonymous, users are unable to access their own clickstream information. 

Access by individual users to their temporarily stored personal information awaiting delivery to an advertiser also is not possible, given the limitations of currently available technology and Unicast's concerns about the privacy of other users' personal information that is also being stored on its servers. 

**What anonymous information is collected on visitors to the Unicast Corporate Web site?**

Anonymous clickstream information is collected for every visitor to this Web site and stored securely on our server. This includes pages viewed, date and time, IP addresses and system information (i.e., browser type). 

This information is used to determine domain type and in some cases, geographic region of the visitor. None of this information is personally identifiable -- it is anonymous. There is no association between this information and a visitor's identity. 

**How is this anonymous information used?**  
The information we collect is used for internal review and is then discarded. We look at the domain names and the page visits of our visitors in order to analyze how we can improve the content of our Web site. 

This information is not stored permanently but rather used temporarily and then discarded. We do not share this information with other organizations, nor do we utilize this information for any other commercial purposes. 

Unicast's principal server is located in the United States and its headquarters are located in New York City. This policy and all legal obligations of Unicast are subject to the laws of New York and the United States, regardless of the location of the user. 

Any claims or complaints against Unicast must be filed in the United States in the courts located in the City and State of New York or with the U.S. Federal authorities. 

**What happens if Unicast changes its privacy policy?**

Unicast reserves the right to make changes to its privacy policy at any time. If Unicast changes its privacy policy in any way, the changes will be posted here to inform users of this fact before they are put into effect and said changes will apply only to information and data collected after the changes have been posted here. 

**How is Unicast involved in industry-wide efforts to protect Web users' privacy?**

Unicast works with recognized trade associations and privacy groups that are actively shaping privacy policies and support consumer privacy. We participate in the Direct Marketing Association and support its efforts to establish industry guidelines that safeguard the right to privacy. 

Unicast is an active member and on the board of directors of the Internet Advertising Bureau, and is a founding member of the Rich Media Special Interest Group. 

Additionally, Unicast is a member of The Association of American Advertising Agencies (AAAA), the Ad Club of New York, the New York New Media Association and The Future of Advertising Stakeholders (FAST). 

If you have any questions, concerns or comments, please e-mail [info@unicast.com](mailto:info@unicast.com). Privacy-related inquires should also be addressed to info@unicast.com. You also may call us at 415-247-1300, or mail us at UNICAST, 650 Fifth Avenue, 9th Floor, New York, NY 10019. Attention: Privacy concerns. 

_Unicast® and The Superstitial® are trademarks of Unicast Communications, New York, NY, USA. All site content is copyrighted by Unicast: © Unicast 1999._

_Unicast reserves the right to share all information collected in the course of its business to successors in business and purchasers of SUPERSTITIAL technology assets_

_The Superstitial® delivery system technology is patent-pending._

_This Site is located in the U.S.A. and is intended for the U.S.-based Internet advertising industry. U.S. and New York State law apply._
